const questions = [
    {
        question: "ØªÙØªÙƒØ± Ø¨Ù†Ùƒ CIB Ø§ØªØ§Ø³Ø³ Ø³Ù†Ø© ÙƒØ§Ù…ØŸ",
        optionA: "1989",
        optionB: "1975",
        optionC: "1960",
        optionD: "1955",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },

    {
        question: "CIB Ø¹Ù†Ø¯Ù‡ ÙƒØ§Ù… ÙØ±Ø¹ Ø¹Ù„Ù‰ Ù…Ø³ØªÙˆÙ‰ Ù…ØµØ±ØŸ ",
        optionA: "50+ ",
        optionB: "100+ ",
        optionC: "150+ ",
        optionD: "200+ ",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },

    {
        question: "ØªØ¹Ø±Ù Ø£ÙˆÙ„ Ø§Ø³Ù… Ù„Ø¨Ù†Ùƒ CIBØŸ ",
        optionA: "Chase National Bank ",
        optionB: "Ø§Ù„Ø¨Ù†Ùƒ Ø§Ù„Ø£Ù‡Ù„ÙŠ Ø§Ù„ØªØ¬Ø§Ø±ÙŠ ",
        optionC: "Ø¨Ù†Ùƒ Chase Ø§Ù„Ø¯ÙˆÙ„ÙŠ ",
        optionD: "Ø§Ù„Ø¨Ù†Ùƒ Ø§Ù„ØªØ¬Ø§Ø±ÙŠ Chase ",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },

    {
        question: "ØªÙØªÙƒØ± Ø¹Ø¯Ø¯ Ø§Ù„Atms CIB ÙƒØ§Ù… ØŸ",
        optionA: "Ø£ÙƒØªØ± Ù…Ù† 1000 ",
        optionB: "Ø£ÙƒØªØ± Ù…Ù† 1400 ",
        optionC: "Ø£ÙƒØªØ± Ù…Ù† 1600 ",
        optionD: "Ø£ÙƒØªØ± Ù…Ù† 1800 ",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },

    {
        question: "ØªÙØªÙƒØ± Ø£Ø¹Ù„Ù‰ limit Ù„Ù„ØªØ­ÙˆÙŠÙ„ Ø§Ù„ÙÙˆØ±ÙŠ Ù…Ù† CIB Mobile Banking app Ø¨ÙŠÙƒÙˆÙ† Ù‚Ø¯ Ø¥ÙŠÙ‡ØŸ",
        optionA: "5 M",
        optionB: "10 M",
        optionC: "15 M",
        optionD: "20 M",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },

    {
        question: "CIB â€¯Ù…ÙˆØ¬ÙˆØ¯ ÙÙŠÙ† Ø¨Ø±Ù‡ Ù…ØµØ±ØŸ ",
        optionA: "Ø£Ù…Ø±ÙŠÙƒØ§ ",
        optionB: "Ø§Ù„Ø³Ø¹ÙˆØ¯ÙŠØ© ",
        optionC: "ØªÙˆÙ†Ø³ ",
        optionD: "ÙƒÙŠÙ†ÙŠØ§  ",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },

    {
        question: "Ø±Ù‚Ù… Ø§Ù„Ù€Call Center â€¯Ø¨ØªØ§Ø¹ CIB  Ø£ÙŠÙ‡ØŸ  ",
        optionA: "19666 ",
        optionB: "19555 ",
        optionC: "19444 ",
        optionD: "19333 ",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },

    {
        question: "ØªÙ‚Ø¯Ø± ØªÙØªØ­ Ø­Ø³Ø§Ø¨ myCIB Ù„Ùˆ Ø¹Ù†Ø¯Ùƒ ÙƒØ§Ù… Ø³Ù†Ø©ØŸ  ",
        optionA: "12 ",
        optionB: "15 ",
        optionC: "18 ",
        optionD: "21 ",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },

    {
        question: "ØªÙ‚Ø¯Ø± ØªÙ‚Ø¯Ù… Ø¹Ù„Ù‰ Ø¨Ø·Ø§Ù‚Ø© Ø§Ø¦ØªÙ…Ø§Ù†ÙŠØ© Ø£Ø³Ø§Ø³ÙŠØ© Ù„Ùˆ Ø¹Ù†Ø¯Ùƒ ÙƒØ§Ù… Ø³Ù†Ø©ØŸ ",
        optionA: "16 ",
        optionB: "18 ",
        optionC: "20 ",
        optionD: "21 ",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },

    {
        question: "Ø¥ÙŠÙ‡ Ø§Ù„Ù€Minimum Balance Ø¹Ù„Ø´Ø§Ù† Ø§Ù„Ø¹Ù…ÙŠÙ„ ÙŠÙƒÙˆÙ† ÙÙŠ Ù‚Ø·Ø§Ø¹ PlusØŸ ",
        optionA: "100,000 ",
        optionB: "200,000 ",
        optionC: "300,000 ",
        optionD: "500,000 ",
        correctOption: "optionC"
    },
    {
        question: "Ø¥ÙŠÙ‡ Ø§Ù„Ù€Minimum Balance Ø¹Ù„Ø´Ø§Ù† Ø§Ù„Ø¹Ù…ÙŠÙ„ ÙŠÙƒÙˆÙ† ÙÙŠ Ù‚Ø·Ø§Ø¹ WealthØŸ ",
        optionA: "500,000 ",
        optionB: "1,000,000 ",
        optionC: "1,500,000 ",
        optionD: "2,000,000 ",
        correctOption: "optionC"
    },

    {
        question: "Ø¥ÙŠÙ‡ Ø§Ù„Ù€Minimum Balance Ø¹Ù„Ø´Ø§Ù† Ø§Ù„Ø¹Ù…ÙŠÙ„ ÙŠÙƒÙˆÙ† ÙÙŠ Ù‚Ø·Ø§Ø¹ PrivateØŸ ",
        optionA: "10,000,000 ",
        optionB: "12,000,000 ",
        optionC: "15,000,000 ",
        optionD: "20,000,000 ",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },

    {
        question: "Ø¥ÙŠÙ‡ Ø§Ù„Ù€Credit Card  Ø§Ù„Ù„ÙŠ Ø¹Ù…Ù„Ø§Ø¡ CIB Private Ø¨Ø³ ÙŠÙ‚Ø¯Ø±ÙˆØ§ ÙŠØ·Ù„Ø¹ÙˆÙ‡ØŸ ",
        optionA: "World Card ",
        optionB: "Platinum Card ",
        optionC: "Titanium Card ",
        optionD: "Metal Card ",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },

    {
        question: "Ù…Ø­ØªØ§Ø¬ Ø¥ÙŠÙ‡ Ø¹Ù„Ø´Ø§Ù† ØªÙØªØ­ Ø­Ø³Ø§Ø¨ myCIBØŸ ",
        optionA: "Ø§Ù„Ø¨Ø·Ø§Ù‚Ø© Ø¨Ø³ ",
        optionB: "Ø§Ù„Ø¨Ø·Ø§Ù‚Ø© ÙˆØ¥Ø«Ø¨Ø§Øª Ø¯Ø®Ù„ ",
        optionC: "Ø§Ù„Ø¨Ø·Ø§Ù‚Ø© ÙˆØ¬ÙˆØ§Ø² Ø§Ù„Ø³ÙØ± ",
        optionD: "Ø§Ù„Ø¨Ø·Ø§Ù‚Ø© ÙˆØ´Ù‡Ø§Ø¯Ø© Ø¯Ø±Ø§Ø³ÙŠØ© ",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },

    {
        question: "Ø¨Ø·Ø§Ù‚Ø© CIB World Elite Ø¨ØªØ¯ÙŠ ÙƒØ§Ù… BONUS Point Ø¹Ù„Ù‰ ÙƒÙ„ Ø¬Ù†ÙŠÙ‡ Ø¨ØªØ¯ÙØ¹Ù‡ Ø¨ÙŠÙ‡Ø§ Ø¬ÙˆÙ‡ Ù…ØµØ±ØŸ ",
        optionA: "1 BONUS Points ",
        optionB: "2 BONUS Points ",
        optionC: "3 BONUS Points ",
        optionD: "4 BONUS Points ",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },

    {
        question: "Ø¥ÙŠÙ‡ Ù…Ù† Ø§Ù„Ø®Ø¯Ù…Ø§Øª Ø¯ÙŠ Ù…Ù…ÙƒÙ† ØªÙ†Ø¬Ø²Ù‡Ø§ Ù…Ù† CIB Mobile Banking AppØŸ ",
        optionA: "ØªØ±Ø¨Ø· Ø´Ù‡Ø§Ø¯Ø§Øª Ø£Ùˆ ÙˆØ¯Ø§Ø¦Ø¹ ",
        optionB: "ØªØ³Ø¯Ø¯ Ù…Ø³ØªØ­Ù‚Ø§Øª Ø§Ù„Ù€Credit Card ",
        optionC: "ØªÙ‚Ø¯Ù… Ø¹Ù„Ù‰ Ù‚Ø±Ø¶ Ø£Ùˆ ÙƒØ±ÙŠØ¯ÙŠØª ÙƒØ§Ø±Ø¯ ",
        optionD: "ÙƒÙ„Ù‡ ÙˆØ®Ø¯Ù…Ø§Øª ØªØ§Ù†ÙŠØ© ÙƒØªÙŠØ± ğŸ˜‰ ",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    }


]
let shuffledQuestions = [] //empty array to hold shuffled selected questions

function handleQuestions() {
    //function to shuffle and push 5 questions to shuffledQuestions array
    while (shuffledQuestions.length <= 4) {
        const random = questions[Math.floor(Math.random() * questions.length)]
        if (!shuffledQuestions.includes(random)) {
            shuffledQuestions.push(random)
        }
    }
}


let questionNumber = 1
let playerScore = 0
let wrongAttempt = 0
let indexNumber = 0

// function for displaying next question in the array to dom
function NextQuestion(index) {
    handleQuestions()
    const currentQuestion = shuffledQuestions[index]
    document.getElementById("question-number").innerHTML = questionNumber
    document.getElementById("player-score").innerHTML = playerScore
    document.getElementById("display-question").innerHTML = currentQuestion.question;
    document.getElementById("option-one-label").innerHTML = currentQuestion.optionA;
    document.getElementById("option-two-label").innerHTML = currentQuestion.optionB;
    document.getElementById("option-three-label").innerHTML = currentQuestion.optionC;
    document.getElementById("option-four-label").innerHTML = currentQuestion.optionD;

}


function checkForAnswer() {
    const currentQuestion = shuffledQuestions[indexNumber] //gets current Question 
    const currentQuestionAnswer = currentQuestion.correctOption //gets current Question's answer
    const options = document.getElementsByName("option"); //gets all elements in dom with name of 'option' (in this the radio inputs)
    let correctOption = null

    options.forEach((option) => {
        if (option.value === currentQuestionAnswer) {
            //get's correct's radio input with correct answer
            correctOption = option.labels[0].id
        }
    })

    //checking to make sure a radio input has been checked or an option being chosen
    if (options[0].checked === false && options[1].checked === false && options[2].checked === false && options[3].checked == false) {
        document.getElementById('option-modal').style.display = "flex"
    }

    //checking if checked radio button is same as answer
    options.forEach((option) => {
        if (option.checked === true && option.value === currentQuestionAnswer) {
            document.getElementById(correctOption).style.backgroundColor = "Green"
            playerScore++
            indexNumber++
            //set to delay question number till when next question loads
            setTimeout(() => {
                questionNumber++
            }, 1000)
        }

        else if (option.checked && option.value !== currentQuestionAnswer) {
            const wrongLabelId = option.labels[0].id
            document.getElementById(wrongLabelId).style.backgroundColor = "black"
            document.getElementById(correctOption).style.backgroundColor = "Green"
            wrongAttempt++
            indexNumber++
            //set to delay question number till when next question loads
            setTimeout(() => {
                questionNumber++
            }, 1000)
        }
    })
}



//called when the next button is called
function handleNextQuestion() {
    checkForAnswer();
    unCheckRadioButtons();
    //delays next question displaying for a second
    setTimeout(() => {
        if (indexNumber < shuffledQuestions.length) {
            NextQuestion(indexNumber);
        } else {
            handleEndGame();
        }
        resetOptionBackground();
    }, 1000);
}


//sets options background back to null after display the right/wrong colors
function resetOptionBackground() {
    const options = document.getElementsByName("option");
    options.forEach((option) => {
        document.getElementById(option.labels[0].id).style.backgroundColor = ""
    })
}

// unchecking all radio buttons for next question(can be done with map or foreach loop also)
function unCheckRadioButtons() {
    const options = document.getElementsByName("option");
    for (let i = 0; i < options.length; i++) {
        options[i].checked = false;
    }
}

// function for when all questions being answered
function handleEndGame() {
    let remark = null
    let remarkColor = null

    // condition check for player remark and remark color
    if (playerScore == 5) {
        remark = "Congrats! You won a giveaway"
        remarkColor = "white"
    }

    else if (playerScore < 5) {
        remark = "Hard Luck You Can Try again"
        remarkColor = "white"
    }
    /*
    else if (playerScore >= 7) {
        remark = "Excellent, Keep the good work going."
        remarkColor = "green"
    }*/
    const playerGrade = playerScore;

    //data to display to score board
    document.getElementById('remarks').innerHTML = remark
    document.getElementById('remarks').style.color = remarkColor
    /* document.getElementById('grade-percentage').innerHTML = playerGrade*/
    document.getElementById('wrong-answers').innerHTML = wrongAttempt
    document.getElementById('right-answers').innerHTML = playerScore
    document.getElementById('score-modal').style.display = "flex"

}
document.addEventListener('DOMContentLoaded', function () {
    const nextButton = document.querySelector('.next-button');
    const modalButton = document.querySelector('.modal-button');

    nextButton.addEventListener('click', function () {
        nextButton.classList.toggle('checked');
    });

    modalButton.addEventListener('click', function () {
        modalButton.classList.toggle('checked');
    });
});
//closes score modal and resets game
function closeScoreModal() {
    questionNumber = 1
    playerScore = 0
    wrongAttempt = 0
    indexNumber = 0
    shuffledQuestions = []
    NextQuestion(indexNumber)
    document.getElementById('score-modal').style.display = "none"
}

//function to close warning modal
function closeOptionModal() {
    document.getElementById('option-modal').style.display = "none"
}

// Disable both right-click and touch-and-hold context menus
document.addEventListener('contextmenu', function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
});

// Disable text selection on double click
document.addEventListener('selectstart', function (e) {
    e.preventDefault();
});
